VIRGINIE CORNU

linkedin.com/in/virginiecornu | cornu.virginie@gmail.com

(+33) 683 890 701 •

IT & DATA PROFESSIONAL, MBA BIG DATA MANAGEMENT

IT & Data experienced professional with more than 13 years of experience in both technical and managing roles. Project and team management experiences in Software Development and Business Intelligence. Strong software development, data analysis and database administration skills. Detail-oriented, well organized and proficient at multitasking. Excellent interpersonal and communication skills.

SKILLS

- BI & Data Management
- Team and Project Management
- Agile Methodology
- SQL Server, MongoDB

- Docker, Python, SQL, Javascript, C#, Php
- Mysql, T-SQL, NoSql
- MS BI suite (SSAS, SSRS, SSIS, PowerBI), DWH
- AngularJS, Ionic, IoT, Arduino, Github

WORK EXPERIENCE

MBA INTERN - DATA & ANALYTICS - Virtual Regatta (Online Sailing Game) - Paris, France

2019

In charge of the creation of a new data department. Implement solutions to retrieve, store and analyze data in order to uncover new monetization opportunities. Internship until end of July 2019.

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE MANAGER - Betclic Group (Online Gambling) – Paris, France

2017 - 2018

Provided competitive intelligence and actionable insight to business departments as well as C-level management by identifying drivers of customer loyalty, brand awareness and website usage. Supervised a team of five BI developers and architect based in France and Malta. Directed development and ongoing maintenance of a three-terabyte Data Warehouse, two cubes and a report platform providing over 150 reports to every departments of the company.

- Significantly improved system availability by reducing the loading time of the DWH by 50% (from 15 hours to 7).
- Implemented source control, release management and Agile methodology resulting in better visibility, communication and productivity.
- Reduced by 50% on-call hours by implementing monitoring tools and automating processes.
- Directed and implemented a games recommendation system in python to increase customer engagement.
- Ensured centralized information by writing and maintained KPI definitions documents and data dictionary.

PROJECT DIRECTOR - *OpenField (Real-time data intelligence solution editor) – Paris, France* Coordinated the delivery of our solution to our clients.

2016 - 2017

- Proxy role between our clients and our internal teams, providing day to day direction and statuses.
- Managed resources and oversaw finances to ensure projects progress on time and on budget.
- Supervised and coordinated functional and technical teams as well as external stakeholders.
- Product Owner role to technical team and set up Agile methodology in the company.

Responsible for the IT strategy definition and the implementation all technical areas.

- Defined product roadmap and technical architecture, led Project Management (Agile Methods)
- Developed websites, applications and a foreground extraction service (SaaS).
- Managed databases and BI solutions to follow revenue and engagement

<u>Clothery - Your Dressing App • HUp! – The Digital Treasure Hunt</u>

PRIOR EXPERIENCE

DBA SQL SERVER / BI DEVELOPER - Betclic Everest Group (Online Gambling), France - 2011 – 2015
In addition to day to day DBA activities, selected to drive projects of data migration from Oracle to SQL Server for 2M customers in an international context and implement a full BI solution (DWH and MS BI tools).

SOFTWARE ENGINEER .NET - CONSULTANT - PSA Peugeot Citroën (Automobile Industry) - 2009 - 2011

SOFTWARE ENGINEER .NET / BI DEVELOPER - AIOI Motor (Toyota insurance company), France - 2007 – 2009

SOFTWARE ENGINEER PHP / NLP INTERN - *LIMSI – CNRS (The National Center for Scientific Research) -* 2007 Natural language processing (NLP) role: Developed computational-linguistics module for Named Entity Recognition and Classification. Conducted corpus analysis and developed machine learning algorithms in Java and python. Software engineer role: Developed a document management portal to researchers (Php/MySql).

WEB DEVELOPER - Several positions between 2002 and 2007

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Posture Detector – *IoT Personal project* – *Connected device*

2018

Internet of Things project to prevent back pain by detecting bad posture and correct it immediately.

Posture Detector

NaviShop - *Personal project — Mobile application*

2014

Conception and development of a hybrid mobile application to find shops in Paris subway.

Buy flowers on your way home, get a picture for your passport or buy a croissant on your way to work, these are few examples of how NaviShop can help optimize your travel time.

NaviShop

EDUCATION & ONLINE COURSES

MBA BIG DATA MANAGEMENT AND DECISION PROCESS - ESLSCA, Paris, France - December 2019

FOUR YEARS UNIVERSITY DEGREE - NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING (NLP) - University Diderot (Paris VII), France - 2007

DATA MINING WITH WEKA - MOOC - *University of Waikato - New Zealand - 2016*

MACHINE LEARNING - MOOC - Coursera - University of Stanford - Learning ongoing

DESIGNING BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE SOLUTIONS WITH SQL SERVER 2012 - EduGroup, Paris - 2013

LANGUAGES

French (Native language) English (Fluent) German (Beginner) Italian (Beginner)

ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS

Technology (Dev, IoT, AI)
Travelling (Europe, America, Oceania)

Music (Piano, Guitar, Violin, Drums)
Sports (Badminton, Snowboard)